cubesmart.com 2018-11-06

# CubeSmart Privacy Policy, Terms and Trademark Usage | CubeSmart

At CubeSmart, we want you to know how we collect, use, share, and protect information about you. By interacting with CubeSmart through our stores and website (www.cubesmart.com) you consent to the use of information that is collected or submitted as described in this Policy (“Policy”). We may change or add to this Policy, so we encourage you to review it periodically.

CubeSmart (collectively, “We”, “Us” or “Our”) is committed to respecting the privacy and security of any information you share with us. We take commercially reasonable steps to handle personal information responsibly. By providing CubeSmart with personal information in person or by using the CubeSmart website or the Network Program website (collectively, the “Site” or “Website”), you consent to the terms of this Policy, together with the Terms and Conditions Agreement for the Site.

**The foregoing Policy is effective as of May 15, 2017.**

**INFORMATION COLLECTED BY CUBESMART**

CubeSmart only collects your personal information through this Site or otherwise when you choose to provide such information in-person, over the phone or otherwise. Personal information includes, but is not limited to, your name, address, telephone number, email address, and credit card number and expiration date (for online bill payment and purchases).

You may review and request changes to your personal information that CubeSmart has collected, including the removal of your personal information from CubeSmart's databases, by writing to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. Complete removal of all information may not be immediate, and in some instances, it may not be possible to delete all archival copies of this information. Further, to the extent you remain a Customer of CubeSmart, an owner, manager or operator of a self-storage facility that is part of the CubeSmart Network or otherwise maintain a business relationship with CubeSmart, we will retain your information for as long as your account is active, or for as long as we deem necessary to provide you services, conduct our business, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

You may also provide personal information about other people, such as their name, address, phone number or email address. This information is only used for the sole purpose of completing your request or for whatever reason it may have been provided, such as referrals.

CubeSmart does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to rent storage or make purchases. If you are under 13, you should not attempt to create an account or send any information about yourself to us, including, but not limited to, your name, address, phone number, or email address. If you believe that CubeSmart may have any information about a child under 13, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) and we will endeavor to delete that information and terminate the child's account from our databases.

**USE OF INFORMATION**

CubeSmart uses personal information to:

  * conduct our business;
  * respond to your inquiry regarding reserving a unit;
  * enable you to make a bill payment online;
  * enable you to purchase products and services online;
  * offer you CubeSmart specials and discounts;
  * provide you with CubeSmart services and information relevant to those services and to our Site;
  * facilitate customer transactions with unaffiliated third-party storage companies that are part of the CubeSmart Network; and
  * develop new CubeSmart services.

**OTHER TECHNOLOGIES**

CubeSmart may also use other technologies to track how visitors use our Site. Such technologies may include, but are not limited to:

**Automated Information Collection**

We may connect information collected automatically with information we already have about you in order to identify you as a CubeSmart Customer. If we are able to identify you as a CubeSmart Customer we may, for example, link your activity on our website to your activity in a CubeSmart store or on a mobile applications. This allows us to provide you with a personalized experience regardless of how you interact with us – online, in store, mobile, etc.

In order to provide the best Customer experience possible, we also use automated information collection technologies for reporting and analysis purposes. We examine metrics such as how you are shopping on our Site, in our stores, and on our mobile applications (if any), the performance of our marketing efforts, and your response to those marketing efforts.

**Cookies and Tracking Technologies**

We and our service providers use cookies, web beacons, and other technologies to receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us through your computer or mobile device. This information, which includes, but is not limited to: the pages you visit on our site or mobile application, which web address you came from, the type of browser/device/hardware you are using, purchase information and checkout process, search terms, and IP-based geographic location, helps us recognize you, customize your website experience and make our marketing messages more relevant. This includes CubeSmart content presented on another website or mobile application.

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by CubeSmart and our marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers, e.g. call tracking platforms. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies to identify customer status, test segmentation, and referral source. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

The DoubleClick DART Cookie is a specific type of cookie used by Google as part of the Google AdSense program. Google uses these cookies to enable itself and its partners to serve ads to users based on their visit to the Site and/or other third-party sites on the Internet. For more information on the DoubleClick DART Cookie, or to opt out of the use of the DoubleClick DART Cookie, please visit http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html.

**Third-Party Automated Collection and Interest-Based Advertising**

CubeSmart participates in interest-based advertising (IBA), also known as Online Behavioral Advertising. We use third-party advertising companies to display ads tailored to your individual interests based on how you browse and shop online.

We allow third-party companies to collect certain information when you visit our Site. This information is used to serve ads for CubeSmart products or services or for the products or services of other companies when you visit this website or other websites. These companies use non-personally-identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over, hardware/software information, cookie and session ID) and personally identifiable information (e.g., static IP address) during your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These parties typically use a cookie, web beacon, or other similar tracking technologies to collect this information.

**Social Media Features and Widgets**

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook “Like” button and Social Media Widgets, such as the Share this button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Social Media Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the Policy of the company providing it.

Our Website includes widgets, which are interactive mini-programs that run on our site to provide specific services from another company (e.g. displaying the news, opinions, music, etc.). Personal information, such as your email address, may be collected through the widget. Cookies may also be set by the widget to enable it to function properly. Information collected by this widget is governed by the Policy of the company that created it.

**Log file**

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

**Local Storage**

We use Local Storage, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LS.

**Do Not Track Policy**

Some web browsers have a “do not track” feature that allows you to inform websites that you do not want to have you online activities tracked. At this time, this website does not respond to web browser-based “do-not-track” signals. However, you may direct our website analytics vendor to not use the data about your visits to this website for our website analytics purposes. Users wanting to opt-out of tracking may configure their browser to disable their cookies. Please review your browser’s help guide for instructions. Please note that this plug-in is being provided by our vendor, and we are not responsible for your use of this plug-in or its effectiveness.

**SECURITY**

Wherever your personal information may be held by CubeSmart or on its behalf, we take reasonable and appropriate steps to secure the information that you provided from unauthorized use or disclosure. The information you provide to access your account and make bill payments or purchases is protected using industry standard e-commerce security technology such as Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology. Please note that, while CubeSmart has endeavored to create a secure and reliable Website for users, the security and confidentiality of any communication transmitted to or from CubeSmart via the Website or email cannot be 100% guaranteed. Accordingly, CubeSmart is not responsible for the security and confidentiality of information transmitted via the Internet.

  * CubeSmart does not share personal information about you with other people or non-affiliated companies except to provide products or services you've requested (including our use of responsible third party vendors), when we have your permission, in the ways that are described in this Policy or under the following circumstances:
  * We respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims
  * We believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of CubeSmart's terms of use, violations of CubeSmart.com’s Terms and Conditions Agreement, or as otherwise required by law.
  * We reserve the right to disclose and transfer your personal information in connection with the sale, assignment, or other transfer of CubeSmart’s business or with the material assets of CubeSmart’s business, or in connection with CubeSmart’s merger with another entity. In these cases, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. Your personal information will then be governed by the new owner’s or manager’s applicable privacy policy.
  * We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.
  * We limit access to personal information about you to personnel who reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order in order to meet business objectives.
  * We use industry standard physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect personal information about you.
  * If we learn of a security systems breach we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps, although we are not committing to do so except as required by law. By using the Site or providing personal information to us, you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy and administrative issues relating to your use of the Site. We may post a notice on our Site if a security breach occurs. If this happens, you will need a web browser enabling you to view the Site. We may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive free written notice of a security breach (or withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice) you should notify us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

**CUSTOMER TESTIMONIALS/COMMENTS/REVIEWS**

We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on the Site, which may contain personal information. We do obtain the customers' consent to post their name, initials or other identifying information posted along with their testimonials via email or other writing prior to posting the testimonials.

Any information and other content (including written works, photos and videos) that you post to the Site will become public information. We cannot control the use of the information and other content that is disclosed publicly, such as on our blogs or social networking pages. You should exercise caution when disclosing information or other content through public pages or blogs, and should refrain from disclosing personal information that you consider to be sensitive. To request removal of your personal information from our blog, community forum or other public page, or if you wish to update or delete your testimonial, contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. Alternatively, if you used a third party application to post such information, you can remove it, by either logging into said application and removing the information or by contacting the appropriate third party application.

**CONTACT PREFERENCES**

When you provide CubeSmart with your contact information, you agree that we may communicate with you about topics of your choosing and send you marketing communications. Generally, when we contact you, we will try to provide you with an easy and convenient way to notify us if you would like further similar communications. To “opt-out” of any further e-mail or contact, send a request to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) CubeSmart will make a good faith effort to comply with such written request within thirty days of receipt of the request.

**QUALITY OF CUSTOMER INFORMATION**

To ensure the quality of our Customer information, the Company periodically compares our current set of customer information to our third party communication providers’ information. The Company deletes Customer contact information if:

  * the Customer has opted out of communication;
  * the Customer has flagged a message as spam;
  * the Customer’s contact information is undeliverable; or
  * the Customer has requested removal.

**CHANGES IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

If we decide to change our Policy, we will post those changes to this Policy, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this Policy, we will notify you on the Site, by email, or by means of a notice on our Policy page prior to the change becoming effective. We will notify internal personnel of changes to this Policy consistent with Company practice and Company will provide an annual reminder to internal personnel of their responsibility to comply with this Policy.

**INTERNATIONAL VISITORS**

This Site is hosted in the United States and is intended for United States visitors. If you are visiting from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from United States law, please note that you are transferring your personal data to the United States and by providing your personal data you are consenting to that transfer. When you provide personal data to CubeSmart or our service providers or vendors, you consent to the processing of your data in the United States as the Site is operated in the United States.

**OTHER SITES**

This Privacy Policy does not apply to other websites which may be operated by affiliates or business partners of CubeSmart even if they are linked to the Site.

Our Site includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of CubeSmart. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. This Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that CubeSmart does not own or control, or to people that CubeSmart does not employ or manage. In addition, some companies that CubeSmart has acquired have their own, preexisting privacy policies, which may be viewed on our acquired companies’ pages.

Please also visit the Terms and Conditions Agreement section of our Site, incorporated here by reference, which explains other important terms governing your use of our Site.

**CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

California law permits users of our Site that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) and include "California Privacy" in the subject line and your request in the body of the communication.

**QUESTIONS OR CONCERNS**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our Policy please email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) You may also contact us at:

CubeSmart  
5 Old Lancaster Road  
Malvern, PA 19355  
(844) 286-7831  
Attn: Chief Legal Counsel
